By now you have seen a lot of different learning algorithms.
到目前为止 我们已经介绍了许多不同的学习算法
And if you've been following along
如果你一直跟着这些视频的进度学习
these videos you should consider
你会发现自己已经不知不觉地
yourself an expert on many state-of-the-art machine learning techniques.
成为一个了解许多先进机器学习技术的专家了
But even among
然而 在懂机器学习的人当中
people that know a certain learning algorithm.
依然存在着很大的差距
There's often a huge difference between
一部分人确实掌握了
someone that really knows how
怎样高效有力地
to powerfully and effectively apply
运用这些学习算法
that algorithm, versus someone that's
而另一些人
less familiar with some of
他们可能对我马上要讲的东西
the material that I'm about
就不是那么熟悉了
to teach and who doesn't really
他们可能没有完全理解
understand how to apply these
怎样运用这些算法
algorithms and can end up
因此总是
wasting a lot of
把时间浪费在
their time trying things out that don't really make sense.
毫无意义的尝试上
What I would like to do is
我想做的是
make sure that if you
确保你在设计
are developing machine learning systems,
机器学习的系统时
that you know how to choose
你能够明白怎样选择
one of the most promising avenues to spend your time pursuing.
一条最合适 最正确的道路
And on this and the next
因此 在这节视频
few videos I'm going to
和之后的几段视频中
give a number of practical
我将向你介绍一些实用的
suggestions, advice, guidelines on how to do that.
建议和指导 帮助你明白怎样进行选择
And concretely what we'd
具体来讲
focus on is the problem
我将重点关注的问题是
of, suppose you are
假如你在开发
developing a machine learning system
一个机器学习系统
or trying to improve the performance
或者想试着改进
of a machine learning system, how
一个机器学习系统的性能
do you go about deciding what are
你应如何决定
the proxy avenues to try
接下来应该
next?
选择哪条道路？
To explain this, let's continue using
为了解释这一问题
our example of learning to
我想仍然使用
predict housing prices.
预测房价的学习例子
And let's say you've implement and regularize linear regression.
假如你已经完成了正则化线性回归
Thus minimizing that cost function
也就是最小化代价函数J的值
j.  Now suppose that
假如
after you take your learn parameters,
在你得到你的学习参数以后
if you test your hypothesis on
如果你要将你的假设函数
the new set of houses, suppose you
放到一组新的房屋样本上进行测试
find that this is making huge
假如说你发现在预测房价时
errors in this prediction of the housing prices.
产生了巨大的误差
The question is what should
现在你的问题是 要想改进这个算法
you then try mixing in order to improve the learning algorithm?
接下来应该怎么办？
There are many things that one
实际上你可以想出
can think of that could improve
很多种方法来改进
the performance of the learning algorithm.
这个算法的性能
One thing they could try, is to get more training examples.
其中一种办法是 使用更多的训练样本
And concretely, you can imagine, maybe, you
具体来讲 也许你能想到
know, setting up phone surveys, going
通过电话调查
door to door, to try to
或上门调查
get more data on how much
来获取更多的
different houses sell for.
不同的房屋出售数据
And the sad thing is I've seen
遗憾的是
a lot of people spend a
我看到好多人花费了好多时间
lot of time collecting more training
想收集更多的训练样本
examples, thinking oh, if we have
他们总认为 噢 要是我有
twice as much or ten times
两倍甚至十倍数量的训练数据
as much training data, that is certainly going to help, right?
那就一定会解决问题的 是吧？
But sometimes getting more training
但有时候 获得更多的训练数据
data doesn't actually help
实际上并没有作用
and in the next few videos
在接下来的几段视频中
we will see why, and we
我们将解释原因
will see how you
我们也将知道
can avoid spending a lot
怎样避免把过多的时间
of time collecting more training data
浪费在收集更多的训练数据上
in settings where it is just not going to help.
这实际上是于事无补的
Other things you might try are
另一个方法 你也许能想到的
to well maybe try a smaller set of features.
是尝试选用更少的特征集
So if you have some set
因此如果你有一系列特征
of features such as x1,
比如x1
x2, x3 and so on,
x2 x3等等
maybe a large number of features.
也许有很多特征
Maybe you want to spend time
也许你可以花一点时间
carefully selecting some small
从这些特征中
subset of them to prevent overfitting.
仔细挑选一小部分来防止过拟合
Or maybe you need to get additional features.
或者也许你需要用更多的特征
Maybe the current set of features
也许目前的特征集
aren't informative enough and you
对你来讲并不是很有帮助
want to collect more data in the sense of getting more features.
你希望从获取更多特征的角度 来收集更多的数据
And once again this is the
同样地
sort of project that can scale
你可以把这个问题
up the huge projects can you
扩展为一个很大的项目
imagine getting phone
比如使用电话调查
surveys to find out more
来获得更多有关
houses, or extra land
或者再进行土地测量
about the pieces of land and so on, so a huge project.
这块土地的信息等等 因此这是一个复杂的问题
And once again it would be
同样的道理
nice to know in advance if
我们非常希望
this is going to help before we
在花费大量时间完成这些工作之前
spend a lot of time doing something like this.
我们就能知道其效果如何
We can also try
我们也可以尝试
adding polynomial features things like
增加多项式特征的方法
x2 square x2 square and product
比如x1的平方 x2的平方
features x1, x2.
x1 x2的乘积
We can still spend quite a
我们可以花很多时间
lot of time thinking about that and
来考虑这一方法
we can also try other things like
我们也可以考虑其他方法
decreasing lambda, the regularization parameter or increasing lambda.
减小或增大正则化参数lambda的值
Given a menu of options
我们列出的这个单子
like these, some of which
上面的很多方法
can easily scale up to
都可以扩展开来
six month or longer projects.
扩展成一个六个月或更长时间的项目
Unfortunately, the most common
遗憾的是
method that people use to
大多数人用来选择这些方法的标准
pick one of these is to go by gut feeling.
是凭感觉的
In which what many people
也就是说
will do is sort of randomly
大多数人的选择方法是
pick one of these options and
随便从这些方法中选择一种
maybe say, "Oh, lets go and get more training data."
比如他们会说 “噢 我们来多找点数据吧”
And easily spend six months collecting
然后花上六个月的时间
more training data or maybe someone
收集了一大堆数据
else would rather be saying, "Well,
然后也许另一个人说
let's go collect a lot more features on these houses in our data set."
“好吧 让我们来从这些房子的数据中多找点特征吧”
And I have a lot
我很遗憾不止一次地看到
of times, sadly seen people spend, you know,
很多人花了
literally 6 months doing one
不夸张地说 至少六个月时间
of these avenues that they have
来完成他们随便选择的一种方法
sort of at random only to
而在六个月或者更长时间后
discover six months later that
他们很遗憾地发现
that really wasn't a promising avenue to pursue.
自己选择的是一条不归路
Fortunately, there is a
幸运的是
pretty simple technique that can
有一系列简单的方法
let you very quickly rule
能让你事半功倍
out half of the things
排除掉单子上的
on this list as being potentially
至少一半的方法
promising things to pursue.
留下那些确实有前途的方法
And there is a very simple technique,
同时也有一种很简单的方法
that if you run, can easily
只要你使用
rule out many of these options,
就能很轻松地排除掉很多选择
and potentially save you
从而为你节省
a lot of time pursuing something that's just is not going to work.
大量不必要花费的时间
In the next two videos
在接下来的两段视频中
after this, I'm going to
我首先介绍
first talk about how to evaluate learning algorithms.
怎样评估机器学习算法的性能
And in the next few
然后在之后的几段视频中
videos after that, I'm
我将开始
going to talk about these techniques,
讨论这些方法
which are called the machine learning diagnostics.
它们也被称为"机器学习诊断法"
And what a diagnostic is, is
“诊断法”的意思是
a test you can run,
这是一种测试法
to get insight into what
你通过执行这种测试
is or isn't working with
能够深入了解
an algorithm, and which will
某种算法到底是否有用
often give you insight as to
这通常也能够告诉你
what are promising things to try
要想改进一种算法的效果
to improve a learning algorithm's
什么样的尝试
performance.
才是有意义的
We'll talk about specific diagnostics later in this video sequence.
在这一系列的视频中我们将介绍具体的诊断法
But I should mention in advance
但我要提前说明一点的是
that diagnostics can take
这些诊断法的执行和实现
time to implement and can sometimes,
是需要花些时间的
you know, take quite a
有时候
lot of time to implement and
确实需要花很多时间
understand but doing so
来理解和实现
can be a very good use
但这样做的确是
of your time when you are
更有效率地利用好你的时间
developing learning algorithms because they
因为这些方法
can often save you from
让你在开发学习算法时
spending many months pursuing an
节省了几个月的时间
avenue that you could
早点从不必要的尝试中解脱出来
have found out much earlier just was not going to be fruitful.
早日脱离苦海
So in the next few
因此
videos, I'm going to first
在接下来几节课中
talk about how evaluate your
我将先来介绍
learning algorithms and after
如何评价你的学习算法
that I'm going to talk
在此之后
about some of these diagnostics which will hopefully
我将介绍一些诊断法
let you much more
希望能让你更清楚
effectively select more of the
在接下来的尝试中
useful things to try mixing
如何选择更有意义的方法
if your goal to improve
最终达到改进机器学习系统性能的目的
the machine learning system.
【教育无边界字幕组】翻译：所罗门捷列夫 校对：Naplessss